<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TaikoIdeas on </title>
    <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/categories/taikoideas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TaikoIdeas on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:06:31 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/categories/taikoideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Freeing The Beat: The Way toward Open Taiko</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/taikoideas/freeingthebeat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:06:31 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/taikoideas/freeingthebeat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A proposal to solve a problem I find myself in.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a awkward-nesss in American Taiko.  When someone tries to join a Taiko group, it is an investment in time and energy.  There is no established canon&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that you immediately play with this new group.  You usually don’t know their repertoire.  For the state of Taiko in America, where most groups only meet once a week, it is hard to join a group without investing a good deal of effort— as it should be!  Taiko Groups are founded on the idea of long term investments and community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiko as Music and Form</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/taikoideas/musicandform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 23:50:50 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/taikoideas/musicandform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recall the words of Tsuji Tasuku, member of Eitetsu Fuunkai:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;If you play Taiko like a drumset, why don&amp;rsquo;t you use a drumset instead?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;He didn&amp;rsquo;t mean that all Taiko pieces need to be loud, but that something about the Taiko must be essential to its playing.  Indeed, utilizing nagado daiko, shime, or uchiwa to create a backbeat that is replaceable with a western drum set with the same effect, feels like a waste.  But, if the appeal of a rhythm or piece necessitates the timbre, choreography, and gravitas of the Taiko, can you be satisfied by saying, &amp;ldquo;There, it&amp;rsquo;s Taiko-ness has been utilized.  We have checked off that box and can proceed to creating of art without worry&amp;rdquo;.  Doesn&amp;rsquo;t that feel just as uncomfortable?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
