<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Year2 on </title>
    <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/tags/year2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Year2 on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 18:04:30 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/tags/year2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: March</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_march/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 18:04:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_march/</guid>
      <description>The Technical side    I have a huge project in the works with Ryan and James. I hope it will be out on arxiv before I head off to NYC on May 14th. It&amp;rsquo;s so exciting that I am spending a lot of time in Lab making sure I get measurements in and getting clean data. The computational projects using DFT or my readings have been pushed out of the way to get this project through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: February</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 23:13:29 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_feb/</guid>
      <description>February was quite a wild ride.
The Technical side    I really learned a ton of things here: In January, I focused on preparing samples for transport measurements while in February, I (re) learned how to do all the experiments I did in the past: Magnetization, transport (on a rotator), heat capacity, and even PXRD. Remembering the basics and how each one fits into a puzzle helped me figure out what I was looking for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: January</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_jan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 23:13:29 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_jan/</guid>
      <description>And we&amp;rsquo;re back! Came back from almost a month break during which I played Taiko in LA, went to Ohio, and got covid&amp;hellip; so no science. Popped back in and hit the ground running pushing projects and getting used to doing research full time.
It feels great being able to accomplish and read things but it feels as if I run around all day making things happen and have one hour of concentrated work a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: November</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 22:26:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_nov/</guid>
      <description>I felt like I really got some momentum back in my research. A little late but a few highlights:
  Restarted DFT calculations and getting into computational condensed matter
  Started a Topological Order Reading Group with Kai and other friends in my year
  Got to know my mentors and got closer to other research group members.
  Decided to stick with James for my Phd</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: October</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_oct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 22:26:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_oct/</guid>
      <description>Some quotes I enjoy.
  &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t like integrals&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;
  Open a bottle when you win a grant. Drink every time something in the experiment fails.
  Some weeks are just sad weeks. Whoops.
  Writing an NSF proposal: Me to my advisor: &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Is this even true?&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; My advisor: &#39;&#39; Probably&#39;&#39;
  I finished a reading course on Quantum Info Meets Quantum Matter by Xiao-Gang Wen along with a few friends that gave me a first glance into topological order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: September</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_sep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 16:32:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_sep/</guid>
      <description>Academically    This month, I spent my time doing a rotation with Mike Zaletel. I looked into Density Matrix Renormalization Group (DMRG) method and topological order in the fractional quantum hall effect. I started to see how computationally nice one dimensional models are, how computationally hard two dimensional models are, and how hard three dimensions is. It fills me with a little sadness to know how hard it is to model three dimensional models.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
