<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:25:48 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lucretius&#39; Dance of Atoms</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/lucretius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/lucretius/</guid>
      <description>Lucretius was a Roman poet and philospher born in 94 BC. He wrote a six volume work called De Rerum Natura or On the nature of things, written in dactylic hexameter and known to detail the main tenants of Epicureanism. It&amp;rsquo;s Book II has this passage in a section known as &amp;lsquo;The Dance of Atoms&amp;rsquo;.
 All bodies of matter are in motion. To understand this best,
Remember that the atoms do not have a place to rest,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LATI Presents: Rei</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20211212-lati-rei/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20211212-lati-rei/</guid>
      <description>   Piece: Rei
Performers: From left to right
 Kohtaro Yamakawa Kara Drapala Adam Shy Mitsue Kajikawa Patsy Matsushita Backline Shime Daniel Olsen Katie Durnbaugh Isaku Kageyama  Composed by: Isaku Kageyama
Taught by: Isaku Kageyama
Location: James Armstrong Theater in Torrance, CA
Thoughts on my playing
 Keep arms up the entire time, looks lazy Left hand is moving before the hit, makign it weaker Look up more, use head more Get lower and closer to the drum Bounce less  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dec 2021 LA Trip</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/dec-2021-la-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 18:33:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/dec-2021-la-trip/</guid>
      <description>From December 3rd to December 12th, 2021 I was back in LA doing private lessons and learning Taiko. This time I was here for a specific reason: Recital + Concert! I took Yuta Kato&amp;rsquo;s Yodan Uchi class, Manman&amp;rsquo;s Quitiplas in the Pocket, and Isaku Kageyama&amp;rsquo;s Rei so that I could perform them in person at the biannual LATI Recial and the &amp;ldquo;Art of Taiko&amp;rdquo; Concert. My week was full with learning Taiko, meeting new Taiko people, and reconnecting with some old ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LATI Presents: Quitiplas in the Pocket</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20211211-lati-quitiplas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20211211-lati-quitiplas/</guid>
      <description>Piece: Quitiplas in the Pocket
ManMan studied Quitiplas (ki-ti-pla) with Venezuelan artist Jackeline Rago in 2013. This music was originally created by the enslaved African-Venezuelan incorporating bamboo sticks when their drums were destroyed and banned by the enslavers. The polyrhythm in quitiplas celebrates freedom of expression and creates a musical conversation that builds community. Empowered by the essence of quitiplas, this taiko piece celebrates the joy of diversity in musical expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LATI Presents: Yodan Uchi</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20211211-lati-yodanuchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20211211-lati-yodanuchi/</guid>
      <description>Piece: Yodan Uchi.
More details about Yodan Uchi: https://taikosource.com/articles/nidan-uchiyodan-uchi/
Performers:
 Fred Visaya Jr. (9) Daniel Olsen (6 Duet) Wendy Ito Wolf Finn (5) Sarah Gilbert (8) Kara Drapala (6 Duet) Katie Durnbaugh (2) Kohtaro Yamakawa (4) Michael Naishtut (1) Noah Garbarino (3) Ariel R (7)  Composed by: Sukeroku Taiko: Kionari Tosha, Saburo Mochizuki, Sado Kobayashi, Yoshihisa Ishikura in 1968.
Taught by: Yuta Kato with official permission to teach by Kionari Tosha and Saburo Mochizuki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yamakawa Presents: Odaiko Zubon Solo</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20211210-odaiko-zubon-solo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 08:13:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20211210-odaiko-zubon-solo/</guid>
      <description>Piece: Odaiko Zubon (Work in Progress) by Kohtaro Yamakawa
Performers: Kohtaro Yamakawa
Composed by: Kohtaro Yamakawa
Video Shot by: Kohtaro Yamakawa
Location: Asano Taiko US Studio in Torrance, CA
Thoughts on my playing
  Softer intro
  Intro needs more level change in legs
  &amp;lsquo;Rich Kid Asshole&amp;rsquo; section needs to be straight arm at the top hits
  More crescendos and change the sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: October</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_oct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 22:26:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_oct/</guid>
      <description>Some quotes I enjoy.
  &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t like integrals&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;
  Open a bottle when you win a grant. Drink every time something in the experiment fails.
  Some weeks are just sad weeks. Whoops.
  Writing an NSF proposal: Me to my advisor: &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Is this even true?&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; My advisor: &#39;&#39; Probably&#39;&#39;
  I finished a reading course on Quantum Info Meets Quantum Matter by Xiao-Gang Wen along with a few friends that gave me a first glance into topological order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I feel</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/20211014_tif/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 12:01:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/20211014_tif/</guid>
      <description>Today I feel happy with my choices that brought me here today.
Today I feel like I made the right choice to work with James&#39; group.
Today is good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cats of Berkeley</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/cats_of_berkeley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:20:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/cats_of_berkeley/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I wish I could write as mysterious as a cat&amp;rdquo;
Edgar Allan Poe
   Sam the cat
      Sam enjoys pets and will stick out his tongue for you
     My partner and I got a visitor one evening   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: September</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_sep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 16:32:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_sep/</guid>
      <description>Academically    This month, I spent my time doing a rotation with Mike Zaletel. I looked into Density Matrix Renormalization Group (DMRG) method and topological order in the fractional quantum hall effect. I started to see how computationally nice one dimensional models are, how computationally hard two dimensional models are, and how hard three dimensions is. It fills me with a little sadness to know how hard it is to model three dimensional models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jiten Daiko Presents: Opening Ceremony</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20210808-nbc-opening-ceremony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 11:39:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20210808-nbc-opening-ceremony/</guid>
      <description>   Pieces Played: Matsuri Daiko
Performers (by solo order):
 Kohtaro Yamakawa Kevin Chen Susanna Elledge Amy Zou Tyler Devlin Galen Rodgers  Taught by: ?
Video Shot by: Buddhist Church of San Francisco
Location: Peace Plaza in Japantown, SF at Nihonmachi Street Fair 2021 Japantown
Thoughts on my playing:
 Keep head up during introductory roll Don&amp;rsquo;t let toes go up Correct head and make the slow Matsuri more tenseful wait a bit more until changing feet of solo Let left hand travel further after hitting ka Head towards the drum during Omiyage B section choreography  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cold Email</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/research-cold-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 12:57:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/research-cold-email/</guid>
      <description>Writing cold emails suck
Balancing between the formality of talking to professors with a candid introduction is tricky. The social anxiety of sending an email to a stranger sends shivers down my spine. I&amp;rsquo;ve sent my fair share of cold emails for starting research projects: here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.
The best cold email is no cold email at all.  Cold Email Alternatives    Find a mutual aquaintance    Unfortunately for those of us with limited social batteries, networking remains the best way to get to know a stranger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Summer Research Reflection</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/2021summerresearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 10:47:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/2021summerresearch/</guid>
      <description>My time with the James Analytis group in the summer of 2021 was fun!
I met a lot of great scientists and learned chemical vapor transport, heat capacity, magnetization, and more. Each group meeting is active and interesting and stimulates great discussion. Above all, I appreciated the freedom. In the beginning, James asked me what I wanted to grow and measure. I took a look at what interested me and found a crystal, grew it, and measured it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jiten Daiko Presents: Juneteenth Corvette Caravan</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20210619-jiten-juneteenth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 17:01:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20210619-jiten-juneteenth/</guid>
      <description>Pieces Played: Matsuri Daiko and Bujinn (not shown)
Performers (by solo order):
 Will Tokunaga Kohtaro Yamakawa Amy Zou Kyle Graycar Joel Graycar  Shime:
 Susanna Elledge Galen Rogers  Narimono:
 Tyler Devlin  Taught by: Isaku Kageyama (Bujinn)
Video Shot by: Ali Kakawa
Location: 762 Fulton Street at Juneteenth Corvette caravan
Thoughts on my playing:
 Keep head up during the oroshi Don&amp;rsquo;t sway your hips so muchduring karaka M3 arm needs to be bigger loop Use more gravity to hit and less acceleration More ma during B section and more spacious rhythms Let the build be more flowy and less erratic More flashy/poses overall Create that golden moment by letting the bachi drop from the furthest point and contorting at the last Better lines on your feet: don&amp;rsquo;t lift the tips of your feet, just heel Glide, don&amp;rsquo;t just move Slower raise of the bachi, use delay and twirls to build atmosphere Way better than before LA trip but not quite where I want to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 2021 LA Trip</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/june-2021-la-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 23:50:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/june-2021-la-trip/</guid>
      <description>I visited LA in the week of June 5th to June 12th and had a blast! A few awesome Taiko things that happened:
 Stayed in Kris Bergstrom and Minh Nguyen&amp;rsquo;s apartment and did jam sessions at his studio! Participated in a UnitOne practice with Jen Baik, Young Kang, Fred Visaya, and Yuta Kato Took a Hachijo and Odaiko/Naname/Yodan private lesson with Yuta Kato Took an Odaiko private lesson with Isaku Kageyama Took a Naname private lesson with Yeeman &amp;ldquo;Manman&amp;rdquo; Mui  My trip to LA was the first time I took a private lesson and the first time I felt I was making a step twoard progressing my Taiko skills and training in a meaninful way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yamakawa Presents: Odaiko Solo Improvisation</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20210607-odaiko-solo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 16:48:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20210607-odaiko-solo/</guid>
      <description>Piece: Odaiko Solo Improvisation by Kohtaro Yamakawa Performers: - Kohtaro Yamakawa
Taught by: Isaku Kageyama
Video Shot by: Isaku Kageyama
Location: Isaku Kageyama studio (North Hollywood)
Thoughts on my playing Prepare better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Teaching Reviews</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/reviews/myteaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 10:58:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/reviews/myteaching/</guid>
      <description>Some fun reviews I&amp;rsquo;ve received while teaching, the good and the bad but not too ugly.
Physics 7B    Praise     In the beginning, God created Physics. But Physics was vicious, so God created Koh, the bastion of defense against all misunderstood attributes of thermodynamics and circuit boards. Koh is Love. Koh is Life. He is an extremely talented GSI who comes prepared every session with worksheets that are so helpful, even other GSIs steal them from him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CU Taiko Presents: Omiyage</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20210527-cutaiko/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 19:17:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20210527-cutaiko/</guid>
      <description>Finished my last piece with Columbia University Taiko playing Omiyage as taught online by Yuta Kato. Soloists in order are Judy, Isaac, Nathan, Koh. My solo was inspired by the Lefty Roam section of Jack Bazaar by Kris Bergstrom.
Piece: Omiyage by Shoji Kameda
Performers: - Judy Chiu - Nathan Kiesman - Serena Luo - Isaac Loomis - Kohtaro Yamakawa
Taught by: Yuta Kato
Video Edited by: Yuta Kato</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeing The Beat: The Way toward Open Taiko</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/freeingthebeat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:06:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/freeingthebeat/</guid>
      <description>A proposal to solve a problem I find myself in.
There is a awkward-nesss in American Taiko. When someone tries to join a Taiko group, it is an investment in time and energy. There is no established canon1 that you immediately play with this new group. You usually don’t know their repertoire. For the state of Taiko in America, where most groups only meet once a week, it is hard to join a group without investing a good deal of effort— as it should be!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back on the 1st Year of my PhD</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 09:53:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_end/</guid>
      <description>Alas we are finished! The first year of the PhD is finished and I am happy. Happy for it to be over. Happy for it to have happened. Many things have occurred in the past year that have made it…. interesting. Unprecedented, you might say.
I took Zoom classes and stayed indoor for the majority of the first half of the year. Fires raged outdoors, COVID ravaged the world, and I was left alone indoors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Effectively</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 21:53:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/tea/</guid>
      <description>Submitted for the Teaching Effectiveness Award)
The main problem all GSI’s faced during the fall of 2020 was engagement. Trying to get non-major students interested and invested in a semester of physics was difficult even without the unprecedented global pandemic. As a first year graduate student, I, too, was thrown into the throes of online learning filled with awkward hellos and being socially distanced from friends. It was hard being a student— desperate to keep my energy up and looking for any kind of break between Zoom classes— and a teacher— driven to engage students but facing the peril of teaching to a wall of black screens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy of Science/Math Articles</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/sciencearticles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 08:41:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/sciencearticles/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read a lot of math and science articles over the past decade. Most were technical, some were pop-sci, and very few were philosphical. These are some of the math/science articles and forum posts that stick in my brain the most! I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with everything written but each gave me something to think about.
Academia and Society      What&amp;rsquo;s a Mathematician to do? by Bill Thurston</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Online Classes</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/onlineclasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:53:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/onlineclasses/</guid>
      <description>Finding a way to get through online classes whether you&amp;rsquo;re a teacher or a student is important. When you&amp;rsquo;re on a few or 10 Zoom meetings a day, here&amp;rsquo;s some things that helped me out in getting through. On average, I spent around 15 hours a week teaching, another 10-15 hours of watching talks and lectures, and a few mor hours to hang out with friends. Here&amp;rsquo;s some tips and tricks to help you get through the day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate School Applications</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/gradapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:51:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/gradapps/</guid>
      <description>I applied to graduate school in physics in the fall of 2020 to be accepted into the fall of 2021. Deciding what to do and when was hard for me. Hopefully this might help others on their own journey.
The Timeline    Freshman/Sophomore Year    The biggest thing to do freshman year is to decide if you want to go to graduate school. To be more specific, you need to decide if you do NOT want to go to graduate school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 1: February</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:25:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_feb/</guid>
      <description>Some new things happened this week. I got permissions to start work at LBNL and on campus.
My became aware of the fantastic world of fractons, finally figured out what Tomonaga Luttinger liqudis were, and became more familiar with the Kitaev model. I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself getting more and more interested in 2D materials and finding out the connection between quantum spin liquids and other strongly correlated systems like unconventional superconductors. I am interested in how abelian/non-abelian anyons may come out of kitaev spin liquids and how they are related to the fact that the QSL must be described by a Conformal Field Theory with central charge c&amp;lt;1/2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 1: Winterbreak</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_winterbreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 15:29:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_winterbreak/</guid>
      <description>With COVID, I didn&amp;rsquo;t go home for the winter break. But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sad. I got the Graduate Remote Instructor Fellowship to study different ways of planning for the (hopefully last) remote semester. I got to seemy partner a lot and explored Berkeley as much as we could. I even got work on my Taiko. It was nice.
Living alone    Once my suite mate left for home in late November for the Thanksgiving holidays, I was by myself!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performances</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/performances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 11:52:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/performances/</guid>
      <description>2021: August 6th - NBC Closing Ceremony of Tokyo Olympics June 18th - Juneteenth Corvette caravan January 23rd- Asano Taiko US Virtual Recital with Jack Bazaar Online
2020: February 21st- East Coast Taiko Conference with CU Taiko
2019: November 10th- Fall Taiko Festival</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about life in undergrad</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:16:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5life/</guid>
      <description>I learned a lot in college, inside and out of classes. There&amp;rsquo;s a tendency to think that just because we are learning so much inside the classroom means that we know a lot about life. I think we all learn at different paces about different parts of life. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found to be true while in undergrad.
1. People are walking contradictions    Especially towards the beginning, I used to really dislike people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about academics in undergrad</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 22:44:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5academia/</guid>
      <description>Being a physics and math major was tough not only in terms of workload but also in getting acclimated to its difficulties. Here&amp;rsquo;s a top 5 list of things I learned while at Columbia!
1. Physics is physical    To me, understanding physics used to mean understanding equations and being able to solve complex problems. However, in doing my major, I discovered the importance of intuition in physics. Creating, leading and developing a practical picture of the world not only helps you approach and solve problems but also gain a deeper understanding of novel phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LATI Presents: The Art and Study of Taiko</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20210123-lati/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 08:15:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/performances/20210123-lati/</guid>
      <description>Learned and performed Jack Bazaar as part of Asano Taiko&amp;rsquo;s Virtual Recital. Had fun meeting Taiko enthusiasts from all over the world (Los Angeles, Berkeley, Little Rock, Calgary, Kawasaki, Buenos Aires) through online asynchronous lessons with Yuta Kato. I believe this was Asano Taiko/LATI&amp;rsquo;s first venture into complete virtual instruction.
Piece: Jack Bazaar by Kris Bergstrom
Performers: - Helen Mcmillan - Hiromi Ashmore - Marty Hilchey - Stacey Nakasone - Marina Roo - Kohtaro Yamakawa</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Semester: Fall 2020</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_fallsem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 15:00:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_fallsem/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks!
Welcome to the first posting in my PhD blog. I hope to continue this throughout my five year journey.
This last year has been an ordeal. I had graduated Columbia at the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic taking my commencement ceremony sitting on my couch at home. We took the 2-3 hours to listen to the commencement ceremony and that was it: the ending of my undergraduate career. It felt a bit empty but it was that way for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Taiko site</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/taikosite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 14:32:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/taikosite/</guid>
      <description>Under inspiration from the superb personal site of Kris Bergstrom, I&amp;rsquo;ll start curating my first personal site on Taiko. I don&amp;rsquo;t aim really to give any instruction or information to any students but I might post some useful links and thoughts that I&amp;rsquo;ve had on my Taiko journey!
Documenting and publishing, albeit to an audience of measure zero, is a process that I want to immerse myself in both so that I can look back on my own progress in the future and maybe even organize my thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookshelf</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/bookshelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:26:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/bookshelf/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m definitely more of a reader than a writer. Like all people, I have some opinions.
Back in the day, CDs and albums belonged on bookshelves as well&amp;hellip; so if you want to know what I listen to, my spotify is here.
Physics Books Normal Books</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physics Bookshelf</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/physicsbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:26:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/physicsbooks/</guid>
      <description>The road to learning physics is full of pitstops and bad diction. Here&amp;rsquo;s some literature to help on the way.
Mechanics     D. Morin&amp;rsquo;s Mechanics H. Goldstein&amp;rsquo;s Classical Mechanics  Quantum Mechanics     D. Griffiths&#39; Introduction to Quantum Mechanics R. Shankar&amp;rsquo;s Principles of Quantum Mechanics S. Weinberg&amp;rsquo;s Lectures on Quantum Mechanics R. Littlejohn&amp;rsquo;s [Lecture Notes] Cohen-Tannoudji&amp;rsquo;s Quantum Mechanics Zettili&amp;rsquo;s Quantum Mechanics  Electromagnetism     D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:15:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I am a physics PhD student at UC Berkeley. I graduated Dublin Scioto HS in 2016 and Columbia University in 2020 with a major in physics and mathematics.
Here is my Resume and CV.
Publications     Nature of the ferromagnetic-antiferromagnetic transition in Y1−xLaxTiO3  [Phys. Rev. B. (2021)]    Two-Dimensional Time-Reversal-Invariant Topological Insulators via Fredholm Theory  [Math. Physics 2020]    Probing the quantum phase transition in Mott insulator BaCoS2 tuned by pressure and Ni substitution  [Phys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taiko as Music and Form</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/musicandform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 23:50:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/taiko/posts/musicandform/</guid>
      <description>I recall the words of Tsuji Tasuku, member of Eitetsu Fuunkai: &amp;ldquo;If you play Taiko like a drumset, why don&amp;rsquo;t you use a drumset instead?&amp;rdquo; He didn&amp;rsquo;t mean that all Taiko pieces need to be loud, but that something about the Taiko must be essential to its playing. Indeed, utilizing nagado daiko, shime, or uchiwa to create a backbeat that is replaceable with a western drum set with the same effect, feels like a waste.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
