<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Koh Yamakawa</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Koh Yamakawa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:25:48 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Taking Online Classes</title>
      <link>/blog/onlineclasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:53:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/onlineclasses/</guid>
      <description>Finding a way to get through online classes whether you&amp;rsquo;re a teacher or a student is important. When you&amp;rsquo;re on a few or 10 Zoom meetings a day, here&amp;rsquo;s some things that helped me out in getting through. On average, I spent around 15 hours a week teaching, another 10-15 hours of watching talks and lectures, and a few mor hours to hang out with friends. Here&amp;rsquo;s some tips and tricks to help you get through the day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year1_Feb</title>
      <link>/blog/year1_feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:25:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/year1_feb/</guid>
      <description>Some new things happened this week. I got permissions to start work at LBNL and on campus.
My became aware of the fantastic world of fractons, finally figured out what Tomonaga Luttinger liqudis were, and became more familiar with the Kitaev model. I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself getting more and more interested in 2D materials and finding out the connection between quantum spin liquids and other strongly correlated systems like unconventional superconductors. I am interested in how abelian/non-abelian anyons may come out of kitaev spin liquids and how they are related to the fact that the QSL must be described by a Conformal Field Theory with central charge c&amp;lt;1/2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 1: Winterbreak</title>
      <link>/blog/year1_winterbreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 15:29:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/year1_winterbreak/</guid>
      <description>With COVID, I didn&amp;rsquo;t go home for the winter break. But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sad. I got the Graduate Remote Instructor Fellowship to study different ways of planning for the (hopefully last) remote semester. I got to seemy partner a lot and explored Berkeley as much as we could. I even got work on my Taiko. It was nice.
Living alone    Once my suite mate left for home in late November for the Thanksgiving holidays, I was by myself!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about life</title>
      <link>/blog/top5life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:16:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/top5life/</guid>
      <description>I learned a lot in college, inside and out of classes. There&amp;rsquo;s a tendency to think that just because we are learning so much inside the classroom means that we know a lot about life. I think we all learn at different paces about different parts of life. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found to be true while in undergrad.
1. People are walking contradictions    Especially towards the beginning, I used to really dislike people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about academics</title>
      <link>/blog/top5academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 22:44:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/top5academia/</guid>
      <description>Being a physics and math major was tough not only in terms of workload but also in getting acclimated to its difficulties. Here&amp;rsquo;s a top 5 list of things I learned while at Columbia!
1. Physics is physical    To me, understanding physics used to mean understanding equations and being able to solve complex problems. However, in doing my major, I discovered the importance of intuition in physics. Creating, leading and developing a practical picture of the world not only helps you approach and solve problems but also gain a deeper understanding of novel phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Semester: Fall 2020</title>
      <link>/blog/year1_fallsem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 15:00:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/year1_fallsem/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks!
Welcome to the first posting in my PhD blog. I hope to continue this throughout my five year journey.
This last year has been an ordeal. I had graduated Columbia at the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic taking my commencement ceremony sitting on my couch at home. We took the 2-3 hours to listen to the commencement ceremony and that was it: the ending of my undergraduate career. It felt a bit empty but it was that way for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Taiko site</title>
      <link>/taiko/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 14:32:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/taiko/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>Under inspiration from the superb personal site of Kris Bergstrom, I&amp;rsquo;ll start curating my first personal site on Taiko. I don&amp;rsquo;t aim really to give any instruction or information to any students but I might post some useful links and thoughts that I&amp;rsquo;ve had on my Taiko journey!
Documenting and publishing, albeit to an audience of measure zero, is a process that I want to immerse myself in both so that I can look back on my own progress in the future and maybe even organize my thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taiko</title>
      <link>/abouttaiko/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 14:32:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abouttaiko/</guid>
      <description>Taiko is a modern art form, originated from the 1950&amp;rsquo;s counterculture movement after the American Occupation of Japan ended. As it spread to America in the 70&amp;rsquo;s, it soon became an art for expression in the Japanese American community. Since then, thousands of Taiko groups have been formed throughout the world, known as the &amp;ldquo;Taiko Boom&amp;rdquo;.
My Background    I started playing Taiko with the Dublin Taiko Group in Dublin, Ohio from sixth grade until I graduated high school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookshelf</title>
      <link>/bookshelf/physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:26:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelf/physics/</guid>
      <description>The road to learning physics meanders. Here&amp;rsquo;s some literature to help on the way.
Mechanics     Goldstein  Quantum Mechanics    Griffiths Shankar
Statistical Mechanics    Kittel- Basics and no more
Electromagnetism    Griffiths Jackson
Condensed Matter    Kittel Ashcroft and Mermin Girvin
Quantum Field Theory    Blundell</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:15:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I am a physics PhD student at UC Berkeley. I graduated Dublin Scioto HS in 2016 and Columbia University in 2020 with a major in physics and mathematics.
Here is my Resume and CV Publications    Click the link to learn more!
  Two-Dimensional Time-Reversal-Invariant Topological Insulators via Fredholm Theory [Math. Physics 2020]   Probing the quantum phase transition in Mott insulator BaCoS2 tuned by pressure and Ni substitution [Phys.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
