<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:25:48 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Teaching Reviews</title>
      <link>/reviews/myteaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 10:58:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reviews/myteaching/</guid>
      <description>Some fun reviews I&amp;rsquo;ve received while teaching, the good and the bad but not too ugly.
Physics 7B    Praise     In the beginning, God created Physics. But Physics was vicious, so God created Koh, the bastion of defense against all misunderstood attributes of thermodynamics and circuit boards. Koh is Love. Koh is Life. He is an extremely talented GSI who comes prepared every session with worksheets that are so helpful, even other GSIs steal them from him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CU Taiko Presents: Omiyage</title>
      <link>/taiko/performances/20210527-cutaiko/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 19:17:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/taiko/performances/20210527-cutaiko/</guid>
      <description>Finished my last piece with Columbia University Taiko playing Omiyage as taught online by Yuta Kato. Soloists in order are Judy, Isaac, Nathan, Koh. My solo was inspired by the Lefty Roam section of Jack Bazaar by Kris Bergstrom.
Piece: Omiyage by Shoji Kameda
Performers: - Judy Chiu - Nathan Kiesman - Serena Luo - Isaac Loomis - Kohtaro Yamakawa
Taught by: Yuta Kato
Video Edited by: Yuta Kato</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeing The Beat</title>
      <link>/posts/taiko/freeingthebeat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:06:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/taiko/freeingthebeat/</guid>
      <description>A proposal to solve a problem I find myself in.
There is a awkward-nesss in American Taiko. When someone tries to join a Taiko group, it is an investment in time and energy. There is no established canon1 that you immediately play with this new group. You usually don’t know their repertoire. For the state of Taiko in America, where most groups only meet once a week, it is hard to join a group without investing a good deal of effort— as it should be!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back on the 1st Year of my PhD</title>
      <link>/posts/diary/year1_end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 09:53:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/diary/year1_end/</guid>
      <description>Alas we are finished! The first year of the PhD is finished and I am happy. Happy for it to be over. Happy for it to have happened. Many things have occurred in the past year that have made it…. interesting. Unprecedented, you might say.
I took Zoom classes and stayed indoor for the majority of the first half of the year. Fires raged outdoors, COVID ravaged the world, and I was left alone indoors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Effectively</title>
      <link>/posts/tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 21:53:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tea/</guid>
      <description>Submitted for the Teaching Effectiveness Award)
The main problem all GSI’s faced during the fall of 2020 was engagement. Trying to get non-major students interested and invested in a semester of physics was difficult even without the unprecedented global pandemic. As a first year graduate student, I, too, was thrown into the throes of online learning filled with awkward hellos and being socially distanced from friends. It was hard being a student— desperate to keep my energy up and looking for any kind of break between Zoom classes— and a teacher— driven to engage students but facing the peril of teaching to a wall of black screens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Online Classes</title>
      <link>/posts/onlineclasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:53:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/onlineclasses/</guid>
      <description>Finding a way to get through online classes whether you&amp;rsquo;re a teacher or a student is important. When you&amp;rsquo;re on a few or 10 Zoom meetings a day, here&amp;rsquo;s some things that helped me out in getting through. On average, I spent around 15 hours a week teaching, another 10-15 hours of watching talks and lectures, and a few mor hours to hang out with friends. Here&amp;rsquo;s some tips and tricks to help you get through the day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate School Applications</title>
      <link>/posts/gradapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:51:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gradapps/</guid>
      <description>I applied to graduate school in physics in the fall of 2020 to be accepted into the fall of 2021. Deciding what to do and when was hard for me. Hopefully this might help others on their own journey.
The Timeline    Freshman/Sophomore Year    The biggest thing to do freshman year is to decide if you want to go to graduate school. To be more specific, you need to decide if you do NOT want to go to graduate school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 1: Winterbreak</title>
      <link>/posts/diary/year1_winterbreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 15:29:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/diary/year1_winterbreak/</guid>
      <description>With COVID, I didn&amp;rsquo;t go home for the winter break. But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sad. I got the Graduate Remote Instructor Fellowship to study different ways of planning for the (hopefully last) remote semester. I got to seemy partner a lot and explored Berkeley as much as we could. I even got work on my Taiko. It was nice.
Living alone    Once my suite mate left for home in late November for the Thanksgiving holidays, I was by myself!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performances</title>
      <link>/taiko/performances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 11:52:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/taiko/performances/</guid>
      <description>2021: January 23rd- Asano Taiko US Virtual Recital with Jack Bazaar Online
2020: February 21st- East Coast Taiko Conference with CU Taiko
2019: November 10th- Fall Taiko Festival</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about life in undergrad</title>
      <link>/posts/diary/top5life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:16:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/diary/top5life/</guid>
      <description>I learned a lot in college, inside and out of classes. There&amp;rsquo;s a tendency to think that just because we are learning so much inside the classroom means that we know a lot about life. I think we all learn at different paces about different parts of life. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found to be true while in undergrad.
1. People are walking contradictions    Especially towards the beginning, I used to really dislike people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about academics in undergrad</title>
      <link>/posts/diary/top5academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 22:44:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/diary/top5academia/</guid>
      <description>Being a physics and math major was tough not only in terms of workload but also in getting acclimated to its difficulties. Here&amp;rsquo;s a top 5 list of things I learned while at Columbia!
1. Physics is physical    To me, understanding physics used to mean understanding equations and being able to solve complex problems. However, in doing my major, I discovered the importance of intuition in physics. Creating, leading and developing a practical picture of the world not only helps you approach and solve problems but also gain a deeper understanding of novel phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LATI Presents: The Art and Study of Taiko</title>
      <link>/taiko/performances/20210123-lati/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 08:15:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/taiko/performances/20210123-lati/</guid>
      <description>Learned and performed Jack Bazaar as part of Asano Taiko&amp;rsquo;s Virtual Recital. Had fun meeting Taiko enthusiasts from all over the world (Los Angeles, Berkeley, Little Rock, Calgary, Kawasaki, Buenos Aires) through online asynchronous lessons with Yuta Kato. I believe this was Asano Taiko/LATI&amp;rsquo;s first venture into complete virtual instruction.
Piece: Jack Bazaar by Kris Bergstrom
Performers: - Helen Mcmillan - Hiromi Ashmore - Marty Hilchey - Stacey Nakasone - Marina Roo - Kohtaro Yamakawa</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Semester: Fall 2020</title>
      <link>/posts/diary/year1_fallsem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 15:00:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/diary/year1_fallsem/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks!
Welcome to the first posting in my PhD blog. I hope to continue this throughout my five year journey.
This last year has been an ordeal. I had graduated Columbia at the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic taking my commencement ceremony sitting on my couch at home. We took the 2-3 hours to listen to the commencement ceremony and that was it: the ending of my undergraduate career. It felt a bit empty but it was that way for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Taiko site</title>
      <link>/posts/taiko/taikosite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 14:32:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/taiko/taikosite/</guid>
      <description>Under inspiration from the superb personal site of Kris Bergstrom, I&amp;rsquo;ll start curating my first personal site on Taiko. I don&amp;rsquo;t aim really to give any instruction or information to any students but I might post some useful links and thoughts that I&amp;rsquo;ve had on my Taiko journey!
Documenting and publishing, albeit to an audience of measure zero, is a process that I want to immerse myself in both so that I can look back on my own progress in the future and maybe even organize my thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taiko</title>
      <link>/abouttaiko/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 14:32:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abouttaiko/</guid>
      <description>Taiko is a modern art form, originated from the 1950&amp;rsquo;s counterculture movement after the American Occupation of Japan ended. As it spread to America in the 70&amp;rsquo;s, it soon became an art for expression in the Japanese American community. Since then, thousands of Taiko groups have been formed throughout the world, known as the &amp;ldquo;Taiko Boom&amp;rdquo;.
Background    I started playing Taiko with the Dublin Taiko Group in Dublin, Ohio from sixth grade until I graduated high school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookshelf</title>
      <link>/bookshelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:26:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelf/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m definitely more of a reader than a writer. Like all people, I have some opinions.
Back in the day, CDs and albums belonged on bookshelves as well&amp;hellip; so if you want to know what I listen to, my spotify is here.
Physics Books Normal Books</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physics Bookshelf</title>
      <link>/posts/bookshelf/physicsbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:26:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bookshelf/physicsbooks/</guid>
      <description>The road to learning physics is full of pitstops and bad diction. Here&amp;rsquo;s some literature to help on the way.
Mechanics     D. Morin&amp;rsquo;s Mechanics H. Goldstein&amp;rsquo;s Classical Mechanics  Quantum Mechanics     D. Griffiths&#39; Introduction to Quantum Mechanics R. Shankar&amp;rsquo;s Principles of Quantum Mechanics S. Weinberg&amp;rsquo;s Lectures on Quantum Mechanics R. Littlejohn&amp;rsquo;s [Lecture Notes]  Electromagnetism     D. Griffiths&#39; Introduction to Electrodynamics J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:15:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I am a physics PhD student at UC Berkeley. I graduated Dublin Scioto HS in 2016 and Columbia University in 2020 with a major in physics and mathematics.
Here is my Resume and CV
Publications    Click the link to learn more!
 Two-Dimensional Time-Reversal-Invariant Topological Insulators via Fredholm Theory  [Math. Physics 2020]    Probing the quantum phase transition in Mott insulator BaCoS2 tuned by pressure and Ni substitution  [Phys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taiko as Music and Form</title>
      <link>/posts/taiko/musicandform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 23:50:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/taiko/musicandform/</guid>
      <description>I recall the words of Tsuji Tasuku, member of Eitetsu Fuunkai: &amp;ldquo;If you play Taiko like a drumset, why don&amp;rsquo;t you use a drumset instead?&amp;rdquo; He didn&amp;rsquo;t mean that all Taiko pieces need to be loud, but that something about the Taiko must be essential to its playing. Indeed, utilizing nagado daiko, shime, or uchiwa to create a backbeat that is replaceable with a western drum set with the same effect, feels like a waste.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
