<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COVID on </title>
    <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/categories/covid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in COVID on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 11:39:26 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/categories/covid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jiten Daiko Presents: Opening Ceremony</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/performances/20210808-nbc-opening-ceremony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 11:39:26 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/performances/20210808-nbc-opening-ceremony/</guid>
      <description> Pieces Played: Matsuri Daiko&#xA;Performers (by solo order):&#xA;Kohtaro Yamakawa Kevin Chen Susanna Elledge Amy Zou Tyler Devlin Galen Rodgers Taught by: ?&#xA;Video Shot by: Buddhist Church of San Francisco&#xA;Location: Peace Plaza in Japantown, SF at Nihonmachi Street Fair 2021 Japantown&#xA;Thoughts on my playing:&#xA;Keep head up during introductory roll Don&amp;rsquo;t let toes go up Correct head and make the slow Matsuri more tenseful wait a bit more until changing feet of solo Let left hand travel further after hitting ka Head towards the drum during Omiyage B section choreography </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jiten Daiko Presents: Juneteenth Corvette Caravan</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/performances/20210619-jiten-juneteenth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 17:01:40 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/performances/20210619-jiten-juneteenth/</guid>
      <description>Pieces Played: Matsuri Daiko and Bujinn (not shown)&#xA;Performers (by solo order):&#xA;Will Tokunaga Kohtaro Yamakawa Amy Zou Kyle Graycar Joel Graycar Shime:&#xA;Susanna Elledge Galen Rogers Narimono:&#xA;Tyler Devlin Taught by: Isaku Kageyama (Bujinn)&#xA;Video Shot by: Ali Kakawa&#xA;Location: 762 Fulton Street at Juneteenth Corvette caravan&#xA;Thoughts on my playing:&#xA;Keep head up during the oroshi Don&amp;rsquo;t sway your hips so muchduring karaka M3 arm needs to be bigger loop Use more gravity to hit and less acceleration More ma during B section and more spacious rhythms Let the build be more flowy and less erratic More flashy/poses overall Create that golden moment by letting the bachi drop from the furthest point and contorting at the last Better lines on your feet: don&amp;rsquo;t lift the tips of your feet, just heel Glide, don&amp;rsquo;t just move Slower raise of the bachi, use delay and twirls to build atmosphere Way better than before LA trip but not quite where I want to be.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yamakawa Presents: Odaiko Solo Improvisation</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/performances/20210607-odaiko-solo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 16:48:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/performances/20210607-odaiko-solo/</guid>
      <description>Piece: Odaiko Solo Improvisation by Kohtaro Yamakawa Performers: - Kohtaro Yamakawa&#xA;Taught by: Isaku Kageyama&#xA;Video Shot by: Isaku Kageyama&#xA;Location: Isaku Kageyama studio (North Hollywood)&#xA;Thoughts on my playing Prepare better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CU Taiko Presents: Omiyage</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/performances/20210527-cutaiko/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 19:17:55 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/performances/20210527-cutaiko/</guid>
      <description>Finished my last piece with Columbia University Taiko playing Omiyage as taught online by Yuta Kato. Soloists in order are Judy, Isaac, Nathan, Koh. My solo was inspired by the Lefty Roam section of Jack Bazaar by Kris Bergstrom.&#xA;Piece: Omiyage by Shoji Kameda&#xA;Performers: - Judy Chiu - Nathan Kiesman - Serena Luo - Isaac Loomis - Kohtaro Yamakawa&#xA;Taught by: Yuta Kato&#xA;Video Edited by: Yuta Kato</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LATI Presents: The Art and Study of Taiko</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/performances/20210123-lati/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 08:15:51 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/taiko/performances/20210123-lati/</guid>
      <description>Learned and performed Jack Bazaar as part of Asano Taiko&amp;rsquo;s Virtual Recital. Had fun meeting Taiko enthusiasts from all over the world (Los Angeles, Berkeley, Little Rock, Calgary, Kawasaki, Buenos Aires) through online asynchronous lessons with Yuta Kato. I believe this was Asano Taiko/LATI&amp;rsquo;s first venture into complete virtual instruction.&#xA;Piece: Jack Bazaar by Kris Bergstrom&#xA;Performers: - Helen Mcmillan - Hiromi Ashmore - Marty Hilchey - Stacey Nakasone - Marina Roo - Kohtaro Yamakawa</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
