<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Berkeley on </title>
    <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/tags/berkeley/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Berkeley on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:20:42 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/tags/berkeley/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cats of Berkeley</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/cats_of_berkeley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:20:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/cats_of_berkeley/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I wish I could write as mysterious as a cat&amp;rdquo;
Edgar Allan Poe
   Sam the cat
      Sam enjoys pets and will stick out his tongue for you
     My partner and I got a visitor one evening   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: September</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_sep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 16:32:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_sep/</guid>
      <description>Academically    This month, I spent my time doing a rotation with Mike Zaletel. I looked into Density Matrix Renormalization Group (DMRG) method and topological order in the fractional quantum hall effect. I started to see how computationally nice one dimensional models are, how computationally hard two dimensional models are, and how hard three dimensions is. It fills me with a little sadness to know how hard it is to model three dimensional models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Teaching Reviews</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/reviews/myteaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 10:58:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/reviews/myteaching/</guid>
      <description>Some fun reviews I&amp;rsquo;ve received while teaching, the good and the bad but not too ugly.
Physics 7B    Praise     In the beginning, God created Physics. But Physics was vicious, so God created Koh, the bastion of defense against all misunderstood attributes of thermodynamics and circuit boards. Koh is Love. Koh is Life. He is an extremely talented GSI who comes prepared every session with worksheets that are so helpful, even other GSIs steal them from him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back on the 1st Year of my PhD</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 09:53:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_end/</guid>
      <description>Alas we are finished! The first year of the PhD is finished and I am happy. Happy for it to be over. Happy for it to have happened. Many things have occurred in the past year that have made it…. interesting. Unprecedented, you might say.
I took Zoom classes and stayed indoor for the majority of the first half of the year. Fires raged outdoors, COVID ravaged the world, and I was left alone indoors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Effectively</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 21:53:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/tea/</guid>
      <description>Submitted for the Teaching Effectiveness Award)
The main problem all GSI’s faced during the fall of 2020 was engagement. Trying to get non-major students interested and invested in a semester of physics was difficult even without the unprecedented global pandemic. As a first year graduate student, I, too, was thrown into the throes of online learning filled with awkward hellos and being socially distanced from friends. It was hard being a student— desperate to keep my energy up and looking for any kind of break between Zoom classes— and a teacher— driven to engage students but facing the peril of teaching to a wall of black screens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Online Classes</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/onlineclasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:53:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/onlineclasses/</guid>
      <description>Finding a way to get through online classes whether you&amp;rsquo;re a teacher or a student is important. When you&amp;rsquo;re on a few or 10 Zoom meetings a day, here&amp;rsquo;s some things that helped me out in getting through. On average, I spent around 15 hours a week teaching, another 10-15 hours of watching talks and lectures, and a few mor hours to hang out with friends. Here&amp;rsquo;s some tips and tricks to help you get through the day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 1: February</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:25:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_feb/</guid>
      <description>Some new things happened this week. I got permissions to start work at LBNL and on campus.
My became aware of the fantastic world of fractons, finally figured out what Tomonaga Luttinger liqudis were, and became more familiar with the Kitaev model. I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself getting more and more interested in 2D materials and finding out the connection between quantum spin liquids and other strongly correlated systems like unconventional superconductors. I am interested in how abelian/non-abelian anyons may come out of kitaev spin liquids and how they are related to the fact that the QSL must be described by a Conformal Field Theory with central charge c&amp;lt;1/2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 1: Winterbreak</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_winterbreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 15:29:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_winterbreak/</guid>
      <description>With COVID, I didn&amp;rsquo;t go home for the winter break. But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sad. I got the Graduate Remote Instructor Fellowship to study different ways of planning for the (hopefully last) remote semester. I got to seemy partner a lot and explored Berkeley as much as we could. I even got work on my Taiko. It was nice.
Living alone    Once my suite mate left for home in late November for the Thanksgiving holidays, I was by myself!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Semester: Fall 2020</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_fallsem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 15:00:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_fallsem/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks!
Welcome to the first posting in my PhD blog. I hope to continue this throughout my five year journey.
This last year has been an ordeal. I had graduated Columbia at the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic taking my commencement ceremony sitting on my couch at home. We took the 2-3 hours to listen to the commencement ceremony and that was it: the ending of my undergraduate career. It felt a bit empty but it was that way for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
