<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Top 5 on </title>
    <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/tags/top-5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Top 5 on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:16:01 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/tags/top-5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about life in undergrad</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:16:01 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot in college, inside and out of classes.  There&amp;rsquo;s a tendency to think that just because we are learning so much inside the classroom means that we know a lot about life.  I think we all learn at different paces about different parts of life.  Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found to be true while in undergrad.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-people-are-walking-contradictions&#34;&gt;&#xA;  1. People are walking contradictions&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#1-people-are-walking-contradictions&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Especially towards the beginning, I used to really dislike people.  Like really really really dislike them.  Something that helped me get over this feeling was realizing that people are walking contradictions.  We believe in things but our actions don&amp;rsquo;t always follow that.  We say things but sometimes our actions don&amp;rsquo;t show that.  But even as imperfect beings, we judge others for being imperfect, of not making sense, or of not doing what they say they would do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about academics in undergrad</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 22:44:57 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5academia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being a physics and math major was tough not only in terms of workload but also in getting acclimated to its difficulties.  Here&amp;rsquo;s a top 5 list of things I learned while at Columbia!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-physics-is-physical&#34;&gt;&#xA;  1. Physics is physical&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#1-physics-is-physical&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To me, understanding physics used to mean understanding equations and being able to solve complex problems.  However, in doing my major, I discovered the importance of intuition in physics.  Creating, leading and developing a practical picture of the world not only helps you approach and solve problems but also gain a deeper understanding of novel phenomena.  One of my friends, who just started a PhD at Harvard, had the remarkable ability to always be &lt;em&gt;kind of&lt;/em&gt; right.  When we pressed him on why, he said that he always imagined the solution and massaged the equations to go towards that solution.  At the time, I found that approach to be uncouth: working towards a solution didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like I was solving anything at all.  Not to mention the various mistakes one can make when intuition fails you!  I think I was addicted to the romantic notion of physics of taking the fundamental equations and uncovering a solution via purely mathematical tricks.  Over time, I came to appreciate this approach but found the importance of active diligence against its failure.  Striking that balance between letting the physicality of your equations guide you while allowing that math and rigor to lead you to new, non-intuitive things is vital.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
