<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on </title>
    <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/tags/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 10:58:15 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/tags/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Teaching Reviews</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/reviews/myteaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 10:58:15 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/reviews/myteaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some fun reviews I&amp;rsquo;ve received while teaching, the good and the bad but not too ugly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;physics-7b&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Physics 7B&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#physics-7b&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;praise&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Praise&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;heading-link&#34; href=&#34;#praise&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-link&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; title=&#34;Link to heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;    &lt;span class=&#34;sr-only&#34;&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, God created Physics. But Physics was vicious, so God created Koh, the bastion of defense against all misunderstood attributes of thermodynamics and circuit boards. Koh is Love. Koh is Life. He is an extremely talented GSI who comes prepared every session with worksheets that are so helpful, even other GSIs steal them from him. He is approachable, and tells you things with a refreshing honesty, helping you succeed not by making it easier, but by making you better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Effectively</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 21:53:53 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/tea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Submitted for the Teaching Effectiveness Award in Spring 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main problem all GSI’s faced during the fall of 2020 was engagement.  Trying to get non-major students interested and invested in a semester of physics was difficult even without the unprecedented global pandemic.  As a first year graduate student, I, too, was thrown into the throes of online learning filled with awkward hellos and being socially distanced from friends.  It was hard being a student— desperate to keep my energy up and looking for any kind of break between Zoom classes— and a teacher— driven to engage students but facing the peril of teaching to a wall of black screens.  That fall, I taught PHYS 7B Physics for Scientists and Engineers for non-physics major students with an average of five hundred students per semester.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
