<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Undergrad on Koh Yamakawa</title>
    <link>/categories/undergrad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Undergrad on Koh Yamakawa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:16:01 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/undergrad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about life in undergrad</title>
      <link>/posts/top5life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:16:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/top5life/</guid>
      <description>I learned a lot in college, inside and out of classes. There&amp;rsquo;s a tendency to think that just because we are learning so much inside the classroom means that we know a lot about life. I think we all learn at different paces about different parts of life. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found to be true while in undergrad.
1. People are walking contradictions    Especially towards the beginning, I used to really dislike people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about academics in undergrad</title>
      <link>/posts/top5academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 22:44:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/top5academia/</guid>
      <description>Being a physics and math major was tough not only in terms of workload but also in getting acclimated to its difficulties. Here&amp;rsquo;s a top 5 list of things I learned while at Columbia!
1. Physics is physical    To me, understanding physics used to mean understanding equations and being able to solve complex problems. However, in doing my major, I discovered the importance of intuition in physics. Creating, leading and developing a practical picture of the world not only helps you approach and solve problems but also gain a deeper understanding of novel phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
