<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Year1 on </title>
    <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/tags/year1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Year1 on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 16:32:45 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/tags/year1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: September</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_sep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 16:32:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_sep/</guid>
      <description>Academically    This month, I spent my time doing a rotation with Mike Zaletel. I looked into Density Matrix Renormalization Group (DMRG) method and topological order in the fractional quantum hall effect. I started to see how computationally nice one dimensional models are, how computationally hard two dimensional models are, and how hard three dimensions is. It fills me with a little sadness to know how hard it is to model three dimensional models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 1: February</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:25:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_feb/</guid>
      <description>Some new things happened this week. I got permissions to start work at LBNL and on campus.
My became aware of the fantastic world of fractons, finally figured out what Tomonaga Luttinger liqudis were, and became more familiar with the Kitaev model. I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself getting more and more interested in 2D materials and finding out the connection between quantum spin liquids and other strongly correlated systems like unconventional superconductors. I am interested in how abelian/non-abelian anyons may come out of kitaev spin liquids and how they are related to the fact that the QSL must be described by a Conformal Field Theory with central charge c&amp;lt;1/2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
