<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COVID on </title>
    <link>/tags/covid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in COVID on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:53:40 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/covid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Taking Online Classes</title>
      <link>/posts/onlineclasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:53:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/onlineclasses/</guid>
      <description>Finding a way to get through online classes whether you&amp;rsquo;re a teacher or a student is important. When you&amp;rsquo;re on a few or 10 Zoom meetings a day, here&amp;rsquo;s some things that helped me out in getting through. On average, I spent around 15 hours a week teaching, another 10-15 hours of watching talks and lectures, and a few mor hours to hang out with friends. Here&amp;rsquo;s some tips and tricks to help you get through the day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 1: Winterbreak</title>
      <link>/posts/year1_winterbreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 15:29:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/year1_winterbreak/</guid>
      <description>With COVID, I didn&amp;rsquo;t go home for the winter break. But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sad. I got the Graduate Remote Instructor Fellowship to study different ways of planning for the (hopefully last) remote semester. I got to seemy partner a lot and explored Berkeley as much as we could. I even got work on my Taiko. It was nice.
Living alone    Once my suite mate left for home in late November for the Thanksgiving holidays, I was by myself!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Semester: Fall 2020</title>
      <link>/posts/year1_fallsem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 15:00:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/year1_fallsem/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks!
Welcome to the first posting in my PhD blog. I hope to continue this throughout my five year journey.
This last year has been an ordeal. I had graduated Columbia at the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic taking my commencement ceremony sitting on my couch at home. We took the 2-3 hours to listen to the commencement ceremony and that was it: the ending of my undergraduate career. It felt a bit empty but it was that way for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
