<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on </title>
    <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:20:42 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cats of Berkeley</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/cats_of_berkeley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:20:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/cats_of_berkeley/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I wish I could write as mysterious as a cat&amp;rdquo;
Edgar Allan Poe
   Sam lives on Rose and Cedar street
      Sam enjoys pets and will stick out his tongue for you
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cold Email</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/research-cold-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 12:57:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/research-cold-email/</guid>
      <description>Writing cold emails suck
Balancing between the formality of talking to professors with a candid introduction is tricky. The social anxiety of sending an email to a stranger sends shivers down my spine. I&amp;rsquo;ve sent my fair share of cold emails for starting research projects: here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.
The best cold email is no cold email at all.  Cold Email Alternatives    Find a mutual aquaintance    Unfortunately for those of us with limited social batteries, networking remains the best way to get to know a stranger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Summer Research Reflection</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/2021summerresearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 10:47:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/2021summerresearch/</guid>
      <description>My time with the James Analytis group in the summer of 2021 was fun!
I met a lot of great scientists and learned chemical vapor transport, heat capacity, magnetization, and more. Each group meeting is active and interesting and stimulates great discussion. Above all, I appreciated the freedom. In the beginning, James asked me what I wanted to grow and measure. I took a look at what interested me and found a crystal, grew it, and measured it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back on the 1st Year of my PhD</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 09:53:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_end/</guid>
      <description>Alas we are finished! The first year of the PhD is finished and I am happy. Happy for it to be over. Happy for it to have happened. Many things have occurred in the past year that have made it…. interesting. Unprecedented, you might say.
I took Zoom classes and stayed indoor for the majority of the first half of the year. Fires raged outdoors, COVID ravaged the world, and I was left alone indoors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Effectively</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 21:53:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/tea/</guid>
      <description>Submitted for the Teaching Effectiveness Award)
The main problem all GSI’s faced during the fall of 2020 was engagement. Trying to get non-major students interested and invested in a semester of physics was difficult even without the unprecedented global pandemic. As a first year graduate student, I, too, was thrown into the throes of online learning filled with awkward hellos and being socially distanced from friends. It was hard being a student— desperate to keep my energy up and looking for any kind of break between Zoom classes— and a teacher— driven to engage students but facing the peril of teaching to a wall of black screens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy of Science/Math Articles</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/sciencearticles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 08:41:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/sciencearticles/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read a lot of math and science articles over the past decade. Most were technical, some were pop-sci, and very few were philosphical. These are some of the math/science articles and forum posts that stick in my brain the most! I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with everything written but each gave me something to think about.
Academia and Society      What&amp;rsquo;s a Mathematician to do? by Bill Thurston</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Online Classes</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/onlineclasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:53:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/onlineclasses/</guid>
      <description>Finding a way to get through online classes whether you&amp;rsquo;re a teacher or a student is important. When you&amp;rsquo;re on a few or 10 Zoom meetings a day, here&amp;rsquo;s some things that helped me out in getting through. On average, I spent around 15 hours a week teaching, another 10-15 hours of watching talks and lectures, and a few mor hours to hang out with friends. Here&amp;rsquo;s some tips and tricks to help you get through the day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate School Applications</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/gradapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:51:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/gradapps/</guid>
      <description>I applied to graduate school in physics in the fall of 2020 to be accepted into the fall of 2021. Deciding what to do and when was hard for me. Hopefully this might help others on their own journey.
The Timeline    Freshman/Sophomore Year    The biggest thing to do freshman year is to decide if you want to go to graduate school. To be more specific, you need to decide if you do NOT want to go to graduate school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 1: February</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:25:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_feb/</guid>
      <description>Some new things happened this week. I got permissions to start work at LBNL and on campus.
My became aware of the fantastic world of fractons, finally figured out what Tomonaga Luttinger liqudis were, and became more familiar with the Kitaev model. I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself getting more and more interested in 2D materials and finding out the connection between quantum spin liquids and other strongly correlated systems like unconventional superconductors. I am interested in how abelian/non-abelian anyons may come out of kitaev spin liquids and how they are related to the fact that the QSL must be described by a Conformal Field Theory with central charge c&amp;lt;1/2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 1: Winterbreak</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_winterbreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 15:29:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_winterbreak/</guid>
      <description>With COVID, I didn&amp;rsquo;t go home for the winter break. But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sad. I got the Graduate Remote Instructor Fellowship to study different ways of planning for the (hopefully last) remote semester. I got to seemy partner a lot and explored Berkeley as much as we could. I even got work on my Taiko. It was nice.
Living alone    Once my suite mate left for home in late November for the Thanksgiving holidays, I was by myself!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about life in undergrad</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:16:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5life/</guid>
      <description>I learned a lot in college, inside and out of classes. There&amp;rsquo;s a tendency to think that just because we are learning so much inside the classroom means that we know a lot about life. I think we all learn at different paces about different parts of life. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found to be true while in undergrad.
1. People are walking contradictions    Especially towards the beginning, I used to really dislike people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about academics in undergrad</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 22:44:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5academia/</guid>
      <description>Being a physics and math major was tough not only in terms of workload but also in getting acclimated to its difficulties. Here&amp;rsquo;s a top 5 list of things I learned while at Columbia!
1. Physics is physical    To me, understanding physics used to mean understanding equations and being able to solve complex problems. However, in doing my major, I discovered the importance of intuition in physics. Creating, leading and developing a practical picture of the world not only helps you approach and solve problems but also gain a deeper understanding of novel phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Semester: Fall 2020</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_fallsem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 15:00:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_fallsem/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks!
Welcome to the first posting in my PhD blog. I hope to continue this throughout my five year journey.
This last year has been an ordeal. I had graduated Columbia at the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic taking my commencement ceremony sitting on my couch at home. We took the 2-3 hours to listen to the commencement ceremony and that was it: the ending of my undergraduate career. It felt a bit empty but it was that way for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physics Bookshelf</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/physicsbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:26:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/physicsbooks/</guid>
      <description>The road to learning physics is full of pitstops and bad diction. Here&amp;rsquo;s some literature to help on the way.
Mechanics     D. Morin&amp;rsquo;s Mechanics H. Goldstein&amp;rsquo;s Classical Mechanics  Quantum Mechanics     D. Griffiths&#39; Introduction to Quantum Mechanics R. Shankar&amp;rsquo;s Principles of Quantum Mechanics S. Weinberg&amp;rsquo;s Lectures on Quantum Mechanics R. Littlejohn&amp;rsquo;s [Lecture Notes]  Electromagnetism     D. Griffiths&#39; Introduction to Electrodynamics J.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
