<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on </title>
    <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 21:53:50 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>College Pandtimemic</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/college-pandtimemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 21:53:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/college-pandtimemic/</guid>
      <description>During Pandemic    I wrote the following during the pandemic, in the summer of 2020.
_College graduation is supposed to be a landmark time. Pandemic&amp;rsquo;s are too. Having both at the same time was a bitch.
Being in college is always different. I felt the need of finding that 25th hour of the day and worked day and night with so little sleep that I would snooze at least once a class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: March</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_march/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 18:04:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_march/</guid>
      <description>The Technical side    I have a huge project in the works with Ryan and James. I hope it will be out on arxiv before I head off to NYC on May 14th. It&amp;rsquo;s so exciting that I am spending a lot of time in Lab making sure I get measurements in and getting clean data. The computational projects using DFT or my readings have been pushed out of the way to get this project through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: February</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 23:13:29 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_feb/</guid>
      <description>February was quite a wild ride.
The Technical side    I really learned a ton of things here: In January, I focused on preparing samples for transport measurements while in February, I (re) learned how to do all the experiments I did in the past: Magnetization, transport (on a rotator), heat capacity, and even PXRD. Remembering the basics and how each one fits into a puzzle helped me figure out what I was looking for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Myth of Topology</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/physics/myth_of_topology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 07:36:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/physics/myth_of_topology/</guid>
      <description>Let me be clear. I like topology. And I like how it rears its head in materials.
It has led to the most striking advances in all of condensed matter (Fractional Quantum Hall) and has led to paradigms that allow us to understand things a lot better. BUT, at the same time: it has set ablaze a firestorm of buzz words with little coherency.
Here&amp;rsquo;s all the ways I know about topology in condensed matter: I&amp;rsquo;m going to rant a bit here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: January</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_jan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 23:13:29 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_jan/</guid>
      <description>And we&amp;rsquo;re back! Came back from almost a month break during which I played Taiko in LA, went to Ohio, and got covid&amp;hellip; so no science. Popped back in and hit the ground running pushing projects and getting used to doing research full time.
It feels great being able to accomplish and read things but it feels as if I run around all day making things happen and have one hour of concentrated work a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not giving a F: Professionally</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/dgaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/dgaf/</guid>
      <description>jazz-like approach to physics and nba and comedy and doing what you can knowing your worth and not giving a fuck</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: November</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 22:26:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_nov/</guid>
      <description>I felt like I really got some momentum back in my research. A little late but a few highlights:
  Restarted DFT calculations and getting into computational condensed matter
  Started a Topological Order Reading Group with Kai and other friends in my year
  Got to know my mentors and got closer to other research group members.
  Decided to stick with James for my Phd</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physics Poetry: the Good and the bad</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/physicspoetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/physicspoetry/</guid>
      <description>The good and the bad! In chronological order:
Lucretius (96 BC)     On the Nature of Things: Dance of Atoms (50 BC)  Edgar Allen Poe (1809)     Sonnet to Science (Olbers Paradox) (1848)  James Clerk Maxwell (1831)    Terrible poet but entertaining nonetheless
  Rigid Body Sings (
  A Problem in Dynamics
  John Updike (1932)     Cosmic Gall (on Neutrinos)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lucretius&#39; Dance of Atoms</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/lucretius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/lucretius/</guid>
      <description>Lucretius was a Roman poet and philospher born in 94 BC. He wrote a six volume work called De Rerum Natura or On the nature of things, written in dactylic hexameter and known to detail the main tenants of Epicureanism. It&amp;rsquo;s Book II has this passage in a section known as &amp;lsquo;The Dance of Atoms&amp;rsquo;.
 All bodies of matter are in motion. To understand this best,
Remember that the atoms do not have a place to rest,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: October</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_oct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 22:26:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_oct/</guid>
      <description>Some quotes I enjoy.
  &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t like integrals&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;
  Open a bottle when you win a grant. Drink every time something in the experiment fails.
  Some weeks are just sad weeks. Whoops.
  Writing an NSF proposal: Me to my advisor: &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Is this even true?&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; My advisor: &#39;&#39; Probably&#39;&#39;
  I finished a reading course on Quantum Info Meets Quantum Matter by Xiao-Gang Wen along with a few friends that gave me a first glance into topological order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I feel</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/20211014_tif/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 12:01:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/20211014_tif/</guid>
      <description>Today I feel happy with my choices that brought me here today.
Today I feel like I made the right choice to work with James&#39; group.
Today is good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing an advisor</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/choosing_an_advisor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 12:01:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/choosing_an_advisor/</guid>
      <description>It was surprisingly difficult choosing an advisor in my PhD.
I was choosing between two advisors: James Analytis and Michael Zaletel. They are both wonderful professors with great ideas. Academically speaking, I could not go wrong. In terms of personality, they were quite different. James is outgoing, nice, and very gregarious while Mike was less relaxed but very concentrated on his work. When talking to either of them, I could almost their wealth of knowledge was almost overwhelming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cats of Berkeley</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/cats_of_berkeley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:20:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/cats_of_berkeley/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I wish I could write as mysterious as a cat&amp;rdquo;
Edgar Allan Poe
   Sam the cat
      Sam enjoys pets and will stick out his tongue for you
     My partner and I got a visitor one evening   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 2: September</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_sep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 16:32:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year2_sep/</guid>
      <description>Academically    This month, I spent my time doing a rotation with Mike Zaletel. I looked into Density Matrix Renormalization Group (DMRG) method and topological order in the fractional quantum hall effect. I started to see how computationally nice one dimensional models are, how computationally hard two dimensional models are, and how hard three dimensions is. It fills me with a little sadness to know how hard it is to model three dimensional models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Cold Email</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/research-cold-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 12:57:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/research-cold-email/</guid>
      <description>Writing cold emails suck
Balancing between the formality of talking to professors with a candid introduction is tricky. The social anxiety of sending an email to a stranger sends shivers down my spine. I&amp;rsquo;ve sent my fair share of cold emails for starting research projects: here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.
The best cold email is no cold email at all.  Cold Email Alternatives    Find a mutual aquaintance    Unfortunately for those of us with limited social batteries, networking remains the best way to get to know a stranger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Summer Research Reflection</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/2021summerresearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 10:47:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/2021summerresearch/</guid>
      <description>My time with the James Analytis group in the summer of 2021 was fun!
I met a lot of great scientists and learned chemical vapor transport, heat capacity, magnetization, and more. Each group meeting is active and interesting and stimulates great discussion. Above all, I appreciated the freedom. In the beginning, James asked me what I wanted to grow and measure. I took a look at what interested me and found a crystal, grew it, and measured it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back on the 1st Year of my PhD</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 09:53:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_end/</guid>
      <description>Alas we are finished! The first year of the PhD is finished and I am happy. Happy for it to be over. Happy for it to have happened. Many things have occurred in the past year that have made it…. interesting. Unprecedented, you might say.
I took Zoom classes and stayed indoor for the majority of the first half of the year. Fires raged outdoors, COVID ravaged the world, and I was left alone indoors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Effectively</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 21:53:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/tea/</guid>
      <description>Submitted for the Teaching Effectiveness Award)
The main problem all GSI’s faced during the fall of 2020 was engagement. Trying to get non-major students interested and invested in a semester of physics was difficult even without the unprecedented global pandemic. As a first year graduate student, I, too, was thrown into the throes of online learning filled with awkward hellos and being socially distanced from friends. It was hard being a student— desperate to keep my energy up and looking for any kind of break between Zoom classes— and a teacher— driven to engage students but facing the peril of teaching to a wall of black screens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy of Science/Math Articles</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/sciencearticles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 08:41:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/sciencearticles/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read a lot of math and science articles over the past decade. Most were technical, some were pop-sci, and very few were philosphical. These are some of the math/science articles and forum posts that stick in my brain the most! I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with everything written but each gave me something to think about.
Academia and Society      What&amp;rsquo;s a Mathematician to do? by Bill Thurston</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Online Classes</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/onlineclasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:53:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/onlineclasses/</guid>
      <description>Finding a way to get through online classes whether you&amp;rsquo;re a teacher or a student is important. When you&amp;rsquo;re on a few or 10 Zoom meetings a day, here&amp;rsquo;s some things that helped me out in getting through. On average, I spent around 15 hours a week teaching, another 10-15 hours of watching talks and lectures, and a few mor hours to hang out with friends. Here&amp;rsquo;s some tips and tricks to help you get through the day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate School Applications</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/gradapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:51:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/gradapps/</guid>
      <description>I applied to graduate school in physics in the fall of 2020 to be accepted into the fall of 2021. Deciding what to do and when was hard for me. Hopefully this might help others on their own journey.
The Timeline    Freshman/Sophomore Year    The biggest thing to do freshman year is to decide if you want to go to graduate school. To be more specific, you need to decide if you do NOT want to go to graduate school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 1: February</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:25:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_feb/</guid>
      <description>Some new things happened this week. I got permissions to start work at LBNL and on campus.
My became aware of the fantastic world of fractons, finally figured out what Tomonaga Luttinger liqudis were, and became more familiar with the Kitaev model. I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself getting more and more interested in 2D materials and finding out the connection between quantum spin liquids and other strongly correlated systems like unconventional superconductors. I am interested in how abelian/non-abelian anyons may come out of kitaev spin liquids and how they are related to the fact that the QSL must be described by a Conformal Field Theory with central charge c&amp;lt;1/2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year 1: Winterbreak</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_winterbreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 15:29:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_winterbreak/</guid>
      <description>With COVID, I didn&amp;rsquo;t go home for the winter break. But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sad. I got the Graduate Remote Instructor Fellowship to study different ways of planning for the (hopefully last) remote semester. I got to seemy partner a lot and explored Berkeley as much as we could. I even got work on my Taiko. It was nice.
Living alone    Once my suite mate left for home in late November for the Thanksgiving holidays, I was by myself!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about life in undergrad</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:16:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5life/</guid>
      <description>I learned a lot in college, inside and out of classes. There&amp;rsquo;s a tendency to think that just because we are learning so much inside the classroom means that we know a lot about life. I think we all learn at different paces about different parts of life. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found to be true while in undergrad.
1. People are walking contradictions    Especially towards the beginning, I used to really dislike people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 things I learned about academics in undergrad</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 22:44:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/top5academia/</guid>
      <description>Being a physics and math major was tough not only in terms of workload but also in getting acclimated to its difficulties. Here&amp;rsquo;s a top 5 list of things I learned while at Columbia!
1. Physics is physical    To me, understanding physics used to mean understanding equations and being able to solve complex problems. However, in doing my major, I discovered the importance of intuition in physics. Creating, leading and developing a practical picture of the world not only helps you approach and solve problems but also gain a deeper understanding of novel phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Semester: Fall 2020</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_fallsem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 15:00:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/diary/year1_fallsem/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks!
Welcome to the first posting in my PhD blog. I hope to continue this throughout my five year journey.
This last year has been an ordeal. I had graduated Columbia at the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic taking my commencement ceremony sitting on my couch at home. We took the 2-3 hours to listen to the commencement ceremony and that was it: the ending of my undergraduate career. It felt a bit empty but it was that way for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physics Bookshelf</title>
      <link>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/physicsbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:26:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kohtaroyamakawa.github.io/posts/bookshelf/physicsbooks/</guid>
      <description>The road to learning physics is full of pitstops and bad diction. Here&amp;rsquo;s some literature to help on the way.
Mechanics     D. Morin&amp;rsquo;s Mechanics H. Goldstein&amp;rsquo;s Classical Mechanics  Quantum Mechanics     D. Griffiths&#39; Introduction to Quantum Mechanics R. Shankar&amp;rsquo;s Principles of Quantum Mechanics S. Weinberg&amp;rsquo;s Lectures on Quantum Mechanics R. Littlejohn&amp;rsquo;s [Lecture Notes] Cohen-Tannoudji&amp;rsquo;s Quantum Mechanics Zettili&amp;rsquo;s Quantum Mechanics  Electromagnetism     D.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
